nols.edu 2019-10-16

# Privacy Policy

NOLS is committed to securing any of your data that we collect online and to only collecting what we need to serve our community. 

This policy is designed so that you understand what information is collected by NOLS when you visit our website, what we do with that data, and how you can review/correct your data.

### Personally Identifiable Information (PII)

When you are simply browsing our website we collect very little data about you as a person. We do automatically collect information about how you use the website so that we can make it better and improve the user experience (for example, making our pages flow in the most logical way possible and making it faster to load the pages).  

If you are applying for a NOLS course through the NOLS website, we require that you create an account so you may access specific content related to your requests. If you are downloading content from our site, signing up for a newsletter, or requesting more information from us, we will prompt you to enter additional information such as first and last name, email address, and phone number so that we can best address your requests for information.

We share this type of information within NOLS to use as part of our everyday business practices, such as processing your requested transactions, maintaining your account, and responding to court orders and legal investigations. We also share information within NOLS so that we can offer relevant products, benefits, and services to you.  

When you are no longer an active customer, we may continue to share your information internally as described in this notice.

NOLS does not sell your information to external companies and only shares with key third party partners to leverage their services on your behalf.  You can see more about our use of third party services below.

### Cookies

Like most websites, NOLS websites use cookies to collect information. Cookies are small data files which are placed on your computer or other devices (such as smartphones or tablets) as you browse this website. They are used to “remember” when your computer or device accesses our websites. Cookies are essential for the effective operation of our websites and helping you interact with us online. Please review our cookies policy here for more information. 

We may use cookies to determine whether you have visited our site previously and to save and remember any preferences that you set while using our site. Cookies also allow us to measure activity on our site and to improve your user experience, for example, by remembering your username and viewing preferences, thus allowing you to visit any member-only parts of the site without re-registering. 

NOLS does not sell your information to third parties; however, we do share some information with a limited number of third party companies performing services on our behalf. These services include things such as marketing, website analytics, and payment services. These companies are prohibited from using your personal information for purposes other than those requested by us or required by law.  One such service provider is Hubspot.  For more information on their practices, please see [Hubspot's privacy policy](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy?_ga=2.127201230.276203236.1527175593-600569633.1525470620). 

### Payment Services

NOLS accepts payments in a number of ways.  This section specifically deals with the electronic payments we accept through our website.  NOLS does not store credit card or bank account information.

#### Credit Card Payments 

NOLS uses Stripe, Inc. (Stripe) to allow our visitors to submit online payments with their credit card. For more information, please see the [Stripe privacy policy](https://stripe.com/us/privacy/).

#### Automated Clearing House (ACH) Payments

To allow our students to directly debit from their bank account, NOLS uses Plaid Inc. (“Plaid”) to gather End User’s data from financial institutions. By using the service you grant NOLS and Plaid the right, power, and authority to act on your behalf to access and transmit your personal and financial information from the relevant financial institution. You agree to your personal and financial information being transferred, stored, and processed by Plaid in accordance with the [Plaid privacy policy](https://plaid.com/legal/).

### Chat, and messaging tools

To offer additional ways to engage with our admissions team we leverage chat and messaging tools on our website and as part of our admissions process. For more information, please see [SnapEngage’s privacy policy](https://snapengage.com/privacy-policy/) and [Quiq's privacy policy](https://goquiq.com/privacypolicy/) and [Help Scout's privacy policy](https://www.helpscout.net/company/legal/privacy/) policy.

The NOLS websites are not intended for nor targeted toward children under 13.    

NOLS is headquartered in Lander, Wyoming, United States of America and our websites are also hosted in the United States of America. Any personal information submitted to NOLS will be transferred from your computer to the NOLS database (also in the United States of America) where it will be stored. By providing your personal information you are expressly consenting to this transfer, processing, and use of this data. In some instances you could be submitting information via one of our trusted partners, such as Hubspot. Please refer to the [Hubspot privacy policy](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy) for details about their data transfer policies.

To request a copy of your information please send a request via email to [data_governance@nols.edu](mailto:data_governance@nols.edu) or via mail to NOLS Data Governance 284 Lincoln St., Lander, WY 82520. Requests will be processed in a timely manner. 

You may modify your personal information, address, phone number, and email via your profile on the [NOLS Portal](https://www.nols.edu/portal/account/login/). Name changes require special handling but can also be requested through the NOLS Portal. 

You may also request a correction to your information via email or mail. For email, please send a request to [data_governance@nols.edu](mailto:data_governance@nols.edu). For mail submissions please send requests to NOLS Data Governance, 284 Lincoln St. Lander, WY 82520. Requests will be processed in a timely manner. We reserve the right to maintain certain information for recordkeeping purposes and/or to complete any transactions that are in progress.  

This policy undergoes periodic internal review and will be updated on our website when any changes are made. This policy was last updated on September 12, 2018.
